(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-03T23:56:38.850957",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
白いドレス
A white dress,
花の冠
a flower crown,
世界一の愛を誓う
swearing the greatest love in the world.
「今までで一番綺麗」
"You're the prettiest you've ever been,"
君の不意打ち
your unexpected,
イジワルな人
teasing remark.
「いつもよりカッコいいかも
"Maybe you look cooler than usual!
気のせいですか？」
Is it just my imagination?"
二人は笑う
The two of us laugh.
紹介したい人がいます
There's someone I want to introduce to you,
パパと同じ負けず嫌い
just as stubborn as my dad.
涙もろく
A crybaby,
よく笑う
who laughs a lot,
優しい人なんです
a kind person.
歩いてもいいですか？
Is it okay if we walk together?
「エスコートしてよね」
"Escort me, okay?"
君はナイト
You are my knight,
離さないでね
don't ever let go.
世界一の愛をあげる
I'll give you the greatest love in the world.
ケンカしても
Even when we fight,
落ち込んでても
even when we're down,
君の味方
I'm on your side.
愛に出会う
Meeting love,
君がいるなら
if you're here,
恋は続く
love continues.
運命の人は来る日
The day my destined person comes,
白馬に乗ってやって来ました
he arrived riding a white horse.
現実はそうじゃないけど
Reality isn't quite like that, but...
普通の君が一番好きよ
I love the ordinary you best.
紹介したい人が居ます
There's someone I want to introduce.
うつむいた 慣れない君
Looking down, awkward you.
緊張して噛んじゃうの
Getting nervous and tripping over your words.
来てくれてありがとう
Thank you for coming.
誓ってもいいですか？ 移り気しないでね
May I make a vow? Please don't be fickle.
君のために変えておいたの
I changed it just for you,
世界一のドレス姿
the world's best dress look.
小指の糸 ほどけないよね
The red thread on our pinkies won't untie, right?
ぎゅっと強く愛を編んで
Tightly, strongly weaving our love,
君の隣 恋は続く
by your side, love continues.
笑って決めていたのに パパの涙がつられちゃうジャン
Though I decided to smile, Papa's tears are contagious.
君はウインクして笑い
You winked and smiled,
幸せをありがとう
thank you for the happiness.
目を閉じていいですか？ 大好きでいてね
May I close my eyes? Keep loving me, okay?
意味はないと離さないでね
Don't let go saying it's meaningless,
世界一の愛をあげる
I'll give you the world's best love.
喧嘩しても落ち込んでても
Even if we fight or feel down,
君の味方
I'm always on your side.
愛に出出会う 君がいるなら 恋は続く
Meeting love, if you're here, love continues.
というわけで、コンカプー！
And so, Konkapu~!
魔界の天才ヴァンパイア、夜空メルでーす！
I'm the Demon Realm's genius vampire, Yozora Mel!
イエーイ！みんな盛り上がってますかー？
Yay! Is everyone hyped up?
もうメルがね、ホロライブに来てから5年目みたいなんです。
It seems it's already been 5 years since Mel joined Hololive.
いやー、なんか早いようでね、長いようで...長いようで短い！っていうやつなんですけども...
Wow, time feels so fast, yet long... long, yet short! That kind of feeling, but...
なのでね、今回もいっぱい歌って踊るので、最後まで楽しんでいってください！
So I'll be singing and dancing a lot this time too, please enjoy until the end!
見てってね、ゲストもこの後、あの、たくさんね、お呼びしてるので、楽しんでいってください！
Watch closely, because I've invited many guests coming up after this, so enjoy!
そして！えー、今回もハッシュタグあります！
And! Um, we have a hashtag this time too!
#夜空メル5周年 で、いっぱいスクショとかツイートとか...してくれると嬉しいな！
I'd be happy if you post lots of screenshots and tweets with #夜空メル5周年!
トレンドまで届けてほしいなー、チラッ、チラッ。
I hope we reach the trends~ *glance*, *glance*.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you in advance!
それじゃあ、この後も夜空メルをいっぱい見てってねー！続きは、Webで！
Well then, please keep watching lots of Yozora Mel after this too~! The continuation is on the Web!
俺の名前はかぶ太郎。
My name is Kabutaro.
今日は魔界から来たヴァンパイア、夜空メルとデートである。
Today, I have a date with Yozora Mel, a vampire from the Demon Realm.
みてみて！めっちゃきれいじゃない？
Look, look! Isn't it super pretty?
彼女が目を輝かせた先にあったのは ショーウィンドウに飾られた白い綺麗なドレスだった
What caught her sparkling eyes was a beautiful white dress displayed in a shop window.
こういうの興味あるんだ？
Are you interested in stuff like this?
んー 女の子なら一度は憧れるんじゃない？
Hmm... If you're a girl, wouldn't you long for it at least once?
メルって黒のイメージあるジャン？ こういう白いドレスも着てみたいなん～なんて！
Mel has a black image, right? Just thinking I'd like to try wearing a white dress like this too... or something!
(本音なのか照れ隠しなのか全く掴めない...が 彼女がドレスを着てみたいことだけはわかった。)
(I can't tell at all if she's being genuine or hiding her embarrassment... but I got that she wants to try wearing a dress.)
...覚えとくよ
...I'll keep that in mind.
ん？ 今なんか言った？
Hm? Did you say something just now?
(深夜アニメの主人公かな？)
(Am I a late-night anime protagonist?)
（深夜アニメの主人公かな？立場逆なんじゃ…と僕は心の中で突っ込んだ。）
(Is she a late-night anime protagonist? Aren't our roles reversed...? I thought to myself.)
（本当は聴こえてたけどね…）
(Though I could actually hear you...)
愛してる 聴こえてる？ 君の番
I love you. Can you hear me? It's your turn.
愛してる
I love you.
風の日も 雨の日も
On windy days and rainy days.
Ah Ah
ずっとそばに
Always by your side.
すれ違う金曜日
Passing each other by on Friday.
口をきかない土曜日
Not speaking on Saturday.
曖昧になってく理由
The reasons growing vague.
なんとなく戻って日曜日
Somehow back together on Sunday.
「ごめんなさい」は一緒に口にしてる
Saying "I'm sorry" together.
誰かが言っていた
Someone once said...
愛は育つのが遅いらしい
That love is slow to grow.
ほらほら言葉にしてよ
Come on, put it into words.
もう1回
One more time.
愛してる 聴こえてる？ 君の番
I love you. Can you hear me? It's your turn.
愛してる
I love you.
風の日も 雨の日も
On windy days and rainy days.
ひと笑いしましょう
Let's share a laugh.
忘れないように 螺旋階段の夕焼け
So we won't forget the sunset on the spiral staircase.
広くても 狭くなっても
Whether it's spacious or cramped,
ずっとそばに居る 君
you're always by my side.
壊れかけたインターホン
A half-broken intercom.
シミの付いた壁紙
Stained wallpaper.
荷造り 重なったダンボール
Cardboard boxes stacked up for packing.
どこを切り取っても 思い出がよみがえる
Wherever you look, memories flood back.
新居が楽しみだね
Looking forward to our new home, aren't we?
誰かが言っていた
Someone once said...
幸福とは人を愛すること
That happiness is loving someone.
ねえねえ 約束しよう
Hey, let's make a promise.
永遠に
Forever.
愛してる 聴こえてる？ 君の番
I love you. Can you hear me? It's your turn.
愛してる
I love you.
病める日も 健やかなる日も
In sickness and in health.
ひと笑いしましょう
Let's share a laugh.
この先何十年 繋がっていく未来地図
A map of our future connecting decades ahead.
年をとっても シワが増えても
Even as we age and get more wrinkles,
ずっとそばに居る 君
you're always by my side.
伝えたい 支えたい 見ていたい
I want to tell you, support you, watch over you,
歌いたい 甘えたい ふざけたい
sing with you, lean on you, fool around with you.
一緒に映画を見て泣きたい 君と
I want to watch movies and cry with you.
この先何が起こったとして
No matter what happens from here on,
変わらないことはただ一つ
there is only one thing that won't change.
君が好き
I love you.
愛してる 聴こえてる？ 君の番
I love you. Can you hear me? It's your turn.
愛してる
I love you.
風の日も 雨の日も
On windy days and rainy days.
ひと笑いしましょう
Let's share a laugh.
忘れないように 螺旋階段の夕焼け
So we won't forget the sunset on the spiral staircase.
広くても 狭くなっても
Whether it's spacious or cramped,
ずっと
forever.
愛してる 聴こえてる？ 君の番
I love you. Can you hear me? It's your turn.
愛してる
I love you.
病める日も 健やかなる日も
In sickness and in health.
ひと笑いしましょう
Let's share a laugh.
この先何十年 繋がっていく未来地図
A map of our future connecting decades ahead.
年をとっても シワが増えても
Even as we age and get more wrinkles,
ずっとそばに居る 君
you're always by my side.
ラララ...
La la la...
はい！ということで、メル様、5周年おめでとう！
Alright! So, Mel-sama, congratulations on your 5th anniversary!
ありがとう～！
Thank you~!
イエーイ！メルキッスでーす！
Yay! It's Melkiss!
どもども～！
Thank you, thank you~!
あ、せっかくベンチあるからさ、一緒に座らない？
Ah, since there's a bench, why don't we sit down together?
えっ、そんな！メル様から誘っていただけるなんて…！
Wh-What! To be invited by Mel-sama...!
踊って疲れたでしょ？
You must be tired from dancing, right?
全然疲れてない！
Not tired at all!
あれ？じゃあ座ろうよ、せっかくだしさ。お花見しようよ、お花見！
Huh? Then let's sit down anyway. Let's do cherry blossom viewing!
え、メル様とお花見できるの？！めちゃめちゃ嬉しい！やったー！
What, I get to view cherry blossoms with Mel-sama?! I'm so happy! Yay!
やったー！
Yay!
よいしょ…
Oof...
あー、桜キレイだねー
Ah, the cherry blossoms are so pretty, aren't they?
綺麗ー！
So pretty!
でも、チョコ先生のほうが綺麗だよ
But Choco-sensei is prettier!
えー、そんなのわかんないこと言わないの、メル様
Eh, don't say such silly things, Mel-sama!
メル様、桜に囲まれていつも以上に可愛い！
Mel-sama, surrounded by cherry blossoms, is even cuter than usual!
えー！ありがとう、チョコ先生！
Ehh! Thank you, Choco-sensei!
あ、可愛い！ちょっとファインダー見てください、ほら！
Ah, so cute! Look at the camera, see!
あー、いいよいいよ！
Ah, great, great!
あーいいよいいよ、誰のリスナーであっても…
Ah, great, great, no matter whose listener you are...
チョコ先生も！
Choco-sensei too!
もっと…もっとチーズして？
Strike a better... better pose!
メルが？もっと…んー、足りない？
Mel? More... mm, not enough?
うわー！
Woah!
嬉しい！
So happy!
チョコ先生、もっと近く行っていい？
Choco-sensei, can I sit closer?
え？もっと近く？
Eh? Even closer?
ちょっと遠いでしょ？
It's a bit far, right?
ここほら、一人分空いてるし
Look, there's space for one more person here.
あーね？いいよ
Ah, true? Okay.
いじいじ…いじいじ…
Fidgeting... fidgeting...
もうちょっと近く…もうちょっと？
A little closer... a little bit?
近い…近い…
So close... so close...
今スクショタイムだぞ
Now it's screenshot time.
ドキドキ…アニメが始まりそうである
Heart pounding... feels like an anime is about to start.
エモい！
So emotional!
エモいぞ！構図が…構図だな
So emotional! The composition... what a composition.
チョコ先生、実はさ、メルね、料理教室に最近通ってるんですよ
Choco-sensei, actually, Mel has been attending cooking classes recently.
えーっと、それは…はあちゃまの料理教室？
Umm, is that... Haachama's cooking class?
はあちゃま？いや、はあちゃまに料理習ったら料理じゃないんだよね
Haachama? No, if you learn cooking from Haachama, it's not cooking.
だってメルメルクッキングって相当斬新な…メルメルクッキングでしょ？
Because MelMel Cooking is pretty innovative... It's MelMel Cooking, right?
違うよ！普通の料理だよ！
No! It's normal cooking!
え、食べれる料理を作るってこと？
Eh, you mean making food that's edible?
前も食べれてたわ！
It was edible before too!
がっでむ！
Goddammit!
いやだってほら、チョコ先生いつも誰かにさ、作ってあげてるでしょ？
Well look, Choco-sensei, you're always making food for someone, right?
いや、まあ確かにね
Well, that's true.
だから今度はチョコ先生のためにメルが作ってさ、帰ってきた時にご飯あったら嬉しくない？
So this time, if Mel cooks for Choco-sensei, wouldn't you be happy if dinner was ready when you came home?
え？ってことは…
Eh? Which means...
チョコが疲れて「あーただいま」って帰ってきて…
Choco comes home tired, saying "Ah, I'm home..."
そしたら「あれ？なんかいい匂いが」って言って…
And then saying "Huh? Smells good," and...
リビング行ったら、メル様が…え？
Going to the living room, Mel-sama is... eh?
「そうだよ、お帰りなさい」って
Saying, "That's right, welcome home."
「お帰りなさい」からの？
"Welcome home," and then?
「ご飯にする？」
"Do you want dinner?"
お決まりの「お風呂にする？」
The classic "Do you want a bath?"
「メルにする？」
"Or do you want Mel?"
いやー、もうそんなのご飯に決まってるじゃないですか！
No way, obviously dinner, right?!
メル様最高！おい！
Mel-sama is the best! Hey!
いやーいい奥さんだ、それはもうガチで！ガチで！最高！嬉しい！
What a great wife! Seriously, for real! Best! So happy!
やっぱ持つべきヴァンパイアよね、やっぱメル様なのよ！
She's the vampire everyone needs, it's gotta be Mel-sama!
いやーそれほどでもー
Well, I wouldn't go that far~
チョコ先生、今年はさ、一緒にお風呂入りませんか？
Choco-sensei, this year, why don't we take a bath together?
ん？ん？お風呂？
Mm? Mm? A bath?
お風呂？お風呂？！
A bath? A bath?!
だってメルティキスさ、結構長いじゃん、付き合い
Because MeltyKiss has known each other for quite a long time, right?
いや、まあ確かに
Well, true.
なのにまだお風呂も一緒に寝たこともないんだよ？
Yet we haven't taken a bath or slept together yet!
あ、そうよね、うん
Ah, that's true, yeah.
今までお風呂入ったのって誰と？
Who have you taken a bath with so far?
え、あ、こよーり？
Eh, ah, Koyori?
ああ、こよーり様と
Ah, with Koyori-sama.
スバルとも寝たし、マリンとも寝たけど、まだチョコ先生とは何もしてないんだよ？
I slept with Subaru, and with Marine, but I haven't done anything with Choco-sensei yet!
そうですよねー！
Right!
そうだよ！
Exactly!
チョコはずっと待ってるのに…
Even though Choco has been waiting all this time...
それ言ったら…
But if you say that...
チョコ先生とはちゃんと時間作って一緒にするって言ってたのに…
You said you'd make proper time with Choco-sensei to do it together...
え？あれ？メル待ちだったってこと？
Eh? Huh? You mean you were waiting for Mel?
チョコはずっと待ってたのにー！なんでー！
Choco was waiting the whole time! Why?!
チョコ先生からも来ないよー！メルだって待ってるのにー！
Choco-sensei didn't come either! Even though Mel was waiting too!
本当にー？
Really?
だって、そしたら二番目の女になっちゃう…
But then I'd become the second woman...
チョコが一番だよ！
Choco is number one!
何その顔？
What's with that face?
チョコは一番の女になりたいからさ
Choco wants to be your number one woman.
え、ホロメンとはまだ旅行行ってない？
Eh, you haven't gone on a trip with Holo members yet?
あ、行ってないかも！大人数では行ったけどさ
Ah, maybe not! I went in a big group though.
二人の旅行は行ってないと
No trips for just the two of you then.
皆様！今年メルティキス、お泊り旅行行きます！
Everyone! This year, MeltyKiss is going on an overnight trip!
やったー！言質取りましたー！
Yay! Got it on record!
やったー！
Yay!
いや、もうこんな時間だ！
Woah, look at the time!
メルこのあとさ、用事があるんだよねー
Mel has plans after this, you know.
え？あ、ねねちと…
Eh? Ah, with Nene-chi...
あ、やっべ！じゃ、ちょっとそろそろ行ってくるわ！チョコ、じゃあねー！
Ah, crap! Okay, I better get going! See ya, Choco!
ちょっと待ってよー！旅行先決まってないよー！
Wait a minute! We haven't decided where to go on our trip yet!
私が私の事を愛して
What's wrong with me loving myself?
何が悪いのでしょうか？
Are you jealous?
嫉妬でしょうか？
痛いだとか変わってるとか
Saying I'm cringey or weird,
届きませんね そのリプライ
those replies don't reach me.
大好きなお洋服
Wearing my favorite clothes
大好きなお化粧で
and my favorite makeup,
お決まりのハーフツイン巻いて
curling my iconic half-twintails,
お出かけしよう
let's go out!
日傘持って
Holding my parasol,
ぼっちだって
even if I'm all alone,
幸せだもん！
I'm happy!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute!
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born!
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so calculatingly cute!
気になっちゃうよね？ごめん
You can't help but notice me, right? Sorry!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute!
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for working so hard on myself!
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so precious!
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for having such high feminine charm!
ムカついちゃうよね？ざまあw
It pisses you off, right? Too bad!
貴女は貴女の事だけどうぞ
You do your own thing, go right ahead,
私に干渉しないでください
but please don't interfere with me.
類は友を呼ぶと言うけど…
They say birds of a feather flock together, but...
届きませんね その陰口
your trash talk doesn't reach me.
重い厚底ブーツ
Wearing heavy platform boots,
お気に入りのリュックで
with my favorite backpack,
崩せない前髪 くしでといで
combing my bangs so they don't mess up,
お出かけしよう
let's go out!
軽い女？
An easy girl?
ふざけんな
Don't mess with me!
重すぎるっつーの！
I'm way too heavy, I tell you!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute!
この時代生きてごめん
Sorry for living in this era!
Chu! 目立っててごめん
Chu! Sorry for standing out!
意識しちゃうよね？ごめん
You can't help thinking of me, right? Sorry!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute!
自分磨きしてごめん
Sorry for improving myself!
Chu! ぶりっ子でごめん
Chu! Sorry for playing cute!
虜にしちゃってごめん
Sorry for captivating you!
ムカついちゃうでしょ？ざまあw
It annoys you, right? Too bad!
趣味の違い 変わり者と
Having different tastes, being called weird,
馬鹿にされても
even if I'm made fun of,
曲げたくない 怖くもない
I won't bend, and I'm not scared
あんたらごとき
of people like you!
自分の味方は自分でありたい
I want to be my own greatest ally.
一番大切にしてあげたい
I want to treasure myself most of all.
理不尽な我慢はさせたくない
I don't want to endure unreasonable things.
“それが私”
"That's who I am."
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute!
生まれてきちゃってごめん
Sorry for being born!
Chu! あざとくてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so calculatingly cute!
人生楽しんでごめん
Sorry for enjoying my life!
Chu! 可愛くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so cute!
努力しちゃっててごめん
Sorry for working so hard on myself!
Chu! 尊くてごめん
Chu! Sorry for being so precious!
女子力高くてごめん
Sorry for having such high feminine charm!
ムカついちゃうよね？ざまあw
It pisses you off, right? Too bad!
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try asking me nicely,
ダーリン
darling.
ダーリンあなたは私の言うこと
Darling, you never listen to
全然聞かない
a single word I say.
あれほどやめてって言った
I told you so many times to quit,
煙草もお酒も
both cigarettes and alcohol,
毎日二箱七缶
two packs and seven cans every day,
一日たりとも欠かさず
without missing a single day.
肝臓やられてお釈迦になっても
Even if your liver gives out and you die,
看護してあげないんだから
I won't nurse you back to health!
ああ言っちゃこう言っちゃ てこでもきかない
Saying this and that, stubborn as a mule,
あなたのハートは真っ黒で
your heart is pitch black.
言いたいことは言わないし
You won't say what you want to say,
ねえ そんなの馬鹿みたいじゃない？
hey, isn't that just foolish?
そうじゃない？ じゃない？ じゃない？
Isn't that right? Right? Right?
いつも思わせぶりな感じで
Always playing hard to get,
察してほしい感じで
wanting me to figure it out,
わざと口にしないの
deliberately staying silent—
ずるくない？
isn't that sly?
馬鹿じゃないの？
Are you stupid?
おねがいダーリン 見て聞いて
Please, darling, look and listen.
欲しいのは形のないもの
What I want is something intangible.
馬鹿にしないでわ 見て聞いて
Don't make a fool of me, look and listen.
覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
Peek deep into my eyes,
真っ直ぐ見つめて
gaze straight at me,
おねだりしてみてほしいの
and try asking me nicely!
ダーリン！
Darling!
私はあなたの気持ちを全然知らないわ
I don't know your feelings at all.
あれほど健気に見つめてきたのに 今ではすっかり知らんぷり
I used to look at you so devotedly, but now you act like you don't care.
ていうか それって胡坐書いてるだけなんじゃないんですか
Or rather, aren't you just taking me for granted?
ぶっちゃけ舌先三寸 あなたのおかげで私のハートはボロボロです
Frankly, it's all lip service. Thanks to you, my heart is in tatters!
つれない時はつれないし
When you're cold, you're cold,
そっちが中々言い出さないからいっつも私が舵取りじゃん？
and since you won't speak up, I'm always the one steering, right?
ねぇ なんだか馬鹿みたいじゃない？
Hey, doesn't that make me look like an idiot?
そうじゃない？ じゃない？ じゃない？
Isn't that right? Isn't it? Isn't it?
そんなことしてて楽しいの？
Is doing that really fun?
どこか足元見てる感じで
It feels like you're looking down on me,
値踏みされてる感じで
like you're assessing my worth.
駆け引きやら勝ち負けじゃないじゃない？
Isn't love supposed to be more than mind games and winning or losing?
そういう面倒くさいことしてるから面倒くさいことになるんだよ
Doing complicated stuff like that is why everything gets so complicated!
寡黙なダーリン ねぇ聞いて 切なさは飾りじゃないのよ
Silent Darling, hey listen, my sadness isn't just for show.
よそ見しないで 逃げないで 触ってよ 心の奥の方
Don't look away, don't run away! Touch the depths of my heart.
一瞬のことじゃない おねだりしてはくれないの？
It's not just a fleeting thing... Won't you please ask me?
言葉に出来ない臆病さは
A cowardice that can't be put into words...
強さではないのよ
...isn't real strength, you know.
甘えてないで 口に出してよ
Stop acting spoiled and say it out loud!
もう... ちゃんとこっち向いてっつったら！
Jeez... I told you to face this way properly!
お願いダーリン 見て聞いて 欲しいのは 形のないもの
Please, Darling, look and listen. What I want is something formless.
馬鹿にしないわ 見て聞いて 覗いてよ 瞳の奥の方
I won't make fun of you, look and listen! Peer into the depths of my eyes.
寡黙なダーリン 寝てないで
Silent Darling, don't go to sleep!
暴いてよ 私の素顔を
Uncover my true self!
お願いダーリン そばにいて
Please, Darling, stay by my side!
触らせて 心の奥の方
Let me touch the depths of your heart.
真っ直ぐ見つめて
Look straight at me,
おねだりしてみてほしいの
I want you to try asking me!
お願いダーリン
Please, Darling!
イエーイ！
Yay!
魔界の天才ヴァンパイア、ホロライブ1期生の夜空メルでーす！
I'm the genius vampire of the Demon Realm, Hololive 1st Gen's Yozora Mel!
えーっと、ホロライブ界の天才ヴァンパイア... えー、5期生の桃鈴ねねでーす！
Um, the genius vampire of the Hololive world... er, 5th Gen's Momosuzu Nene!
ふたり合わせて...
And together we are...
せーの！
Ready, set...
ねねメルメルねねです！
NeneMelMelNene!
完璧じゃん！
That was perfect!
いいじゃん！
Nice!
やったー！ この間のバカライブで鍛えられたな！
Yay! We really trained on that recent Baka Live!
ねー！ すごい鍛えられててよかった！ 楽しかったねー！
Right?! It was so great being trained! That was fun!
ねー！
Yeah!
てか、メルメル先輩、5周年？
Wait, Melmel-senpai, 5th anniversary?
そうだよ、5周年だよー！ すごい可愛いー！
That's right, 5th anniversary! So cute!
イエーイ！
Yay!
え、なんか今回のロゴめっちゃ可愛い！ なんかちょっとシックな感じもあって...
Whoa, this anniversary logo is super cute! It's got a slightly classy feel...
そうなんだよ！ ちょっとウェディングっぽい感じ？
Right! It has a bit of a wedding-like feel?
ぽいぽい！ なんかお菓子みたいなイメージだね！
It does, it does! It looks like sweets!
そうだね、ケーキも後ろにあるしね！
Yeah, there's a cake behind us too!
あ、ね、お城すごいね、お城！ ちょっと見え... 見えてないけど...
Ah, look, the castle is amazing! You can't... can't quite see it though...
イエーイ！
Yay!
ちょっとね、これからもね、大先輩なんですけど...
So, going forward too, even though you're my senior...
これ何ですか？ これ
What is this? What's this?
いやいや... ゴマすってるこれ？
No, no... Are you brown-nosing me?
すってないっす！ いや、でもね、これからも...
I'm not! But really, going forward...
よろしく... よろしくお願いしますよー！
I look forward to working with you!
後輩... よろしくね！
As my junior... nice to have you!
後輩としてよろしくね！
As your junior, nice working with you!
ありがとう！ よろしくね！
Thank you! Nice working with you!
じゃあね、メルメル先輩はまだね、こっからもいっぱいやることあると思うので...
Well then, Melmel-senpai still has plenty more lined up today, so...
ありますとも！ まだまだ！
I certainly do! Plenty more!
帰りましょうかね！
Shall I head back now?
え？
Eh?
じゃあ、頑張って！ 頑張ってね！
Alright, do your best! Do your best!
ちょっとちょっとちょっと！ 待って待って待って！
Hold on, hold on! Wait, wait, wait!
あ、あ、あ... おいおいおい！ 何...
Ah, ah, ah... Hey hey hey! What...
まだ返さないよ？
I'm not letting you go back yet!
きゃっ！
Kyaa!
1！ 2！ 3！ 4！ 5！ 起きて！
1! 2! 3! 4! 5! Wake up!
喜びも (喜びも)
Happiness too (Happiness too)
悲しみも (悲しみも)
And sadness too (And sadness too)
あなたさえ 五等分なんです
Even you are divided into five equal parts.
五等分の気持ち
Five equal feelings.
1つ 作り笑いも見抜かれ
1: Even my fake smiles are seen through,
2つ あんたなんか大嫌いよ
2: I totally hate you,
3つ 真っ直ぐなこの気持ち気づいて
3: Notice these straightforward feelings of mine,
4つ 気心がつくとだんだん
4: As we get to know each other, bit by bit,
5つ 分かり合えたね
5: We come to understand one another.
勉強だけじゃなくて 君を知りたいよ
It's not just about studying, I want to get to know you.
大嫌いから (大嫌いから)
From hating you (From hating you)
大好きへと (大好きへと)
To loving you (To loving you)
変わる心についていけないよ
I can't keep up with this changing heart.
どんなことも (どんなことも)
Whatever comes (Whatever comes)
あなたさえ (あなたさえ)
Even you (Even you)
五等分です
Are divided into five equal parts.
でも私、私、私、私、私は あなたが好きよ
But I, I, I, I, I love you!
私 私 は
Me, me...
あなたが好きよ
...I love you!
少し複雑に心の中
My heart feels a bit complex,
でも変わっていく気持ち
but my feelings are changing.
ずっとこんな関係続いたら...いいのにな
If this relationship could just go on forever...
忘れられない想い出も
Unforgettable memories,
これから増えるストーリーも
and stories that will grow from here on—
あなたなしだったら
if you're not in them,
意味がないのよ
they're all meaningless.
ずっとそばで
Always stay by my side...
教えてね
and teach me, okay?
だけど勝手に胸の鼓動高鳴る
Yet my heart starts beating fast on its own.
運命だって
That it's fate...
信じられる
I can believe it.
同じ気持ちね
We feel the same way, don't we?
またいつか いつか いつか いつか この日を夢に見るかな
Someday, someday, will I dream of this day again?
少しずつ変わる想い
My feelings changing bit by bit,
焦りや苛立ち和らいでく
anxiety and frustration melting away.
信じきれる自信
The confidence to fully believe.
胸の奥に隠れてる言葉
Words hidden deep inside my heart.
甘え下手だけどいいですかって
I'm not good at being spoiled, but is it okay?
私ついて行くわ
I will follow you.
いつまでも
Forever and ever,
忘れない
I won't forget.
出会えた奇跡
The miracle of meeting you,
偶然じゃない
it wasn't a coincidence,
そうでしょ？
right?
大嫌いから
From hating you...
大好きへと
to loving you...
変わる心についていきたいよ
I want to follow this changing heart.
どんなことも
No matter what,
あなたさえ
even you...
五等分です
are split into five equal parts.
でも私
But I...
私 私
I... I...
私 私は
I, I am...
ずっと
always...
ずっと ずっと
always, always...
ずっと あなたに
always to you...
愛を誓います
pledging my love!
We are the brides!
Please!
サンキュー、サンキュー！
Thank you, thank you!
すごーい！この曲はあれか、『五等分の花嫁』の曲！
Awesome! Is this song... 'The Quintessential Quintuplets' song?!
あ、そうなんだよー！
Ah, that's right!
なんで今日この5人に集められたかみんなわかる？
Do you all know why the five of us were gathered today?
え、なんで？なんで？
Huh, why? Why?
わかんない！
I don't know!
あ、頭見るんだ！
Ah, look at our heads!
ヘッド！ヘッド！
Head! Head!
コード付きヘッド！
Heads with cords!
そう、この5人で「ねんどろいど」だから歌いたかったんだー！
Right, because the five of us are Nendoroids, I wanted to sing it!
おー！すごい！
Ooh! Amazing!
てことはさ、でもこの曲だと、私達の中から1人選んでもらわなきゃいけないんじゃないの？
Which means... but with this song, doesn't one of us have to be chosen from the group?
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Me! Me! Me! Me!
ちょっと、ちょっと！待って待って！
Wait, wait! Hold on a second!
今日は5周年なんだから、メルの特権！
Today is my 5th anniversary, so it's Mel's privilege!
メルがナンバーワンってこと！
Which means Mel is number one!
ずるーい！
That's not fair!
だめ、だめ！
No way, no way!
おまたせ！遅くなってごめんね
Sorry to keep you waiting! Sorry I'm late.
[かぶ太郎]: 大丈夫だよ！今日はなにしてたの？
[Kabutaro]: That's okay! What were you up to today?
今日はね！ちょこ先生とねねちと～
Today, you see! I was with Choco-sensei and Nene-chi...
ってことがあってさ！めっちゃ楽しかったよ！
...and that happened! It was super fun!
[かぶ太郎]: （楽しそうに話すメルを見て微笑ましい反面、少しもやもやした感情になってしまった。）
[Kabutaro]: (Watching Mel talk so happily was heartwarming, but at the same time, I felt a bit conflicted.)
[かぶ太郎]: （せっかく時間を作ってくれてるのにこんなんじゃダメだな）
[Kabutaro]: (She went through the trouble of making time for me, I shouldn't be like this.)
んー？なんかあった？
Hmm? Did something happen?
[かぶ太郎]: （うまく隠してたつもりだったけどどうやら気づかれたようだった。）
[Kabutaro]: (I thought I was hiding it well, but it seems she noticed.)
[かぶ太郎]: （なんでわかるんだろう…）
[Kabutaro]: (How did she know...?)
えっな、なんで？
Huh? W-Why?
そりゃあ君のことちゃーんと見てますから！わかるよ？
Well, that's because I'm always watching you closely! Of course I can tell.
…いや、その。僕といるときちゃんとも楽しめてるのかなって…
...Well, I was just wondering if you really enjoy your time with me too...
もう！楽しいに決まってるでしょ！じゃなかったらこんなおしゃれして…
Geez! Of course I'm enjoying it! Otherwise, I wouldn't have dressed up like this...
一週間前からずっと楽しみになんかしてないってば！
...or been looking forward to this for an entire week!
[かぶ太郎]: （頬を膨らませて怒るメルを見て不謹慎だけど僕は安心した。）
[Kabutaro]: (Seeing Mel puffing her cheeks in annoyance made me feel relieved, as improper as that might be.)
ていうか 君もそういうこと考えるんだね
I mean, you think about things like that too, huh?
え？
Huh?
ううん、いつもそういうの隠すからさ！ ふふ、可愛いところあるね〜
No, it's just that you usually hide that kind of thing! Hehe, you have a cute side.
あのさ、この間ドレス着てみたいっていってたよね。本当に着てみない？
Hey, you said before that you wanted to try wearing a dress. Do you really want to try one on?
えっ？！着れるの…？！！！
What?! I can wear one...??!!
朝になったら
When morning comes,
二人目を合わせて
our eyes meet,
たわいないこと
and about frivolous things,
少し話したいな
I want to talk a little.
晴れた午後は
On a sunny afternoon,
そっと手をつないで
holding hands gently,
穏やかな街を
through a peaceful town,
少し歩いてみたり
taking a little walk.
そんな想像さえ
Even such imagination
愛おしくて
is so dear to me.
いつまでも同じ時間を
To spend the same time
一緒に過ごしていたくて
together with you forever.
だって朝も夜も
Because morning and night,
伝えたいことたくさんあって
there are so many things I want to tell you.
今日も明日も
Today and tomorrow too,
好きだなんて言えたら
if only I could tell you that I love you...
夜になったら
When night comes,
星の見える場所で
in a place where we can see the stars,
眠りにつくまで
until we fall asleep,
ずっと寄り添っていたいな
I want to stay close by your side.
触れられる距離が愛おしくて
Being close enough to touch is so dear to me.
その声を その体温を
Your voice, your warmth,
もっと感じていたくて
I want to feel them even more.
だって何度も何度も
Because time and time again,
名前を呼んでもまだ足りなくて
no matter how many times I call your name, it's not enough.
今日も明日も
Today and tomorrow too,
そう二人でいれたら
if only the two of us could be together like this...
切ないときは
When you feel sad,
綺麗な花を飾りましょう
let's decorate with beautiful flowers.
悲しいときは
When you feel down,
楽しい話をしましょう
let's talk about fun things.
楽しく話をしましょう
...let me talk about fun things.
髪に 頬に
Just by touching my hair, my cheeks...
ただ触れてくれるだけで
just by touching them,
暗い心も
even a dark heart
瞬間 明るくなるんだって
brightens up in an instant.
朝も 夜も
Morning and night,
叶えたいこと こんなにあって
I have so many wishes I want to come true.
今日も 明日も
Today and tomorrow too,
幸せだと 言えたら
if I could just say I'm happy...
いいのに
...I wish I could.
メルは あなたのこと 愛しています
Mel loves you.
みんなー！
Everyone!
ここまで歌ってきましたけど
I've sung up to here,
どうですかー？
how was it?
楽しんでますかー？
Are you enjoying yourselves?
ここで恒例のね
Now then, for the usual...
みんなお待ちかね 告知タイムに行きたいと思います！
everyone's long-awaited announcement time, let's get to it!
もう5年目になるので みんなも大体流れ分かってきたよね？
It's already been 5 years, so everyone pretty much knows the flow by now, right?
きっとね！
I'm sure!
そう！
That's right!
正解！
Correct!
なんと！
Believe it or not,
この後 夜空メル5周年グッズが販売されます！
Yozora Mel 5th Anniversary merchandise will go on sale right after this!
やったー！
Yay!
まず 1つ目は…
First of all, number one is...
さとうぽて先生描き下ろし アクリルジオラマスタンドー！
an acrylic diorama stand illustrated by Sato Pote-sensei!
なんと このアクリルスタンド ゆらゆら揺れるようになっております！
Amazingly, this acrylic stand is made to sway back and forth!
すごい 可愛いよー！
It's amazing and so cute!
それからね 純白のドレス めちゃくちゃ可愛いので ぜひゲットしてください！
And the pure white dress is super cute too, so please get it!
そして 2つ目ー！
And number two!
は ミシュネ先生描き下ろしの メルと始める新生活クッション！
is the "Start a New Life with Mel Cushion" illustrated by Mishune-sensei!
裏表どちらも ガチ恋距離のメルちゃんがいます！
Both front and back feature Mel at an up-close, loving distance!
気分でね お好きなように使ってください！
Please use it however you like depending on your mood!
君の生活の一部にね メルを置いてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be happy if you make Mel a part of your daily life!
そして 3つ目！
And number three!
メルと契約ネックレスです！
The "Contract with Mel Necklace"!
アクセサリー物は実はメル初めてなので
Accessory merch is actually a first for Mel,
ぜひね これも付けてほしいなー
so I'd really love for you to wear this too!
男の子も女の子もね 着けやすいデザインにメルが監修させていただきましたー！
Mel supervised the design so that both guys and girls can easily wear it!
イエーイ！どう？
Yay! How is it?
これあとね みんな気づいたかな？
Also, did everyone notice?
今回のメインイラスト 実はね メル着けてるんだー！
In this main illustration, Mel is actually wearing it!
なので これを着ければメルとお揃い！
So if you wear this, you'll match with Mel!
そしてメルとずーっと一緒にいるよっていう契約もね 結んだことになるので
And since it means we've made a contract to be together forever...
ぜひ こちらもゲットしてください！
Please be sure to get this one too!
そして！
And!
フルセットで購入してくれた方には メルの直筆サインが…
For those who purchase the full set, Mel's handwritten signature...
つく！
comes with it!
ポストカードが！
A postcard!
もらえます！
You'll get it!
イエーイ！
Yay!
複製メッセージも付いてますので こちらもね お早めに…
It also includes a printed message, so since this one...
数量限定になってるので お早めにお願いしますね！
...is limited in quantity, please get it early!
グッズはこの後21時から販売されます！
The merch will go on sale right after this at 21:00!
心を込めて今回もカキカキしますので よろしくお願いします！
I'll write them with all my heart this time too, so please look forward to it!
ん？
Hmm?
それではね 次の曲で最後になるんですが…
Well then, the next song will be the last one, but...
ガシガシ！今回もメンバー限定でアフターライブを開催しちゃいます！
Surprise! This time too, we'll be holding a members-only after-live stream!
やったー！
Yay!
良かったら お前も株主にならないか？
If you'd like, won't you become a member too?
なので 今のうちにメンバー登録もよろしくお願いします！
So please consider registering for membership in the meantime!
あっという間のライブでしたけど
It felt like such a fast live concert, but...
5年目ももっともっといろんな人が楽しんで メルのことを好きになってくれるよう
so that more and more people can enjoy and come to love Mel in her 5th year...
ホロライブを引っ張っていけるように頑張りますので こんなメル…
I'll do my best to lead Hololive forward, so please keep supporting me!
…だけど これからもよろしくお願いします！
...but I look forward to your continued support from now on!
みんなのことが好きな気持ちを最後まで込めて 次の曲歌います！
Putting all my love for everyone into it until the very end, I'll sing the next song!
合いの手もよろしくお願いします！
Please join in with the calls as well!
はい！３、２、１！
Alright! 3, 2, 1!
…ねぇ、どうかな？似合ってる？
"...Hey, how is it? Does it suit me?"
うん、綺麗だよ
"Yeah, you look beautiful."
ふふーん、ありがと！でもまさかこんな早く着れるとはな〜！
"Hehe, thanks! But I never thought I'd get to wear this so soon~!"
写真だけだけどね…
"It's just for photos, though..."
いやーまさかメルプロポーズされたのかと思っちゃったよ！
"Gosh, I almost thought Mel was getting proposed to!"
いつか…ね
"Someday... right."
ん？なんか言った？
"Hmm? Did you say something?"
いや！なんでもない
"No! It's nothing."
(やっぱりメルは深夜アニメの主人公なのかもしれない。)
"(Maybe Mel really is the main character of a late-night anime.)
あ、そうだ。お礼に…これ受け取ってほしいな
"Ah, that's right. As a token of thanks... I want you to have this."
え？これは…？
"Huh? This is...?"
これはね、代々伝わる大切な人に渡すネックレスだよ。
"This is a necklace passed down through generations, given to someone special."
メルとずっと一緒にいる契を結んだ者だけがつけることができるのだよ！
"Only someone who has bound themselves to be with Mel forever can wear it!"
なにそれこわ！！！ていうか中２病感凄んだけど！？
"What's that, terrifying!!! I mean, the chuunibyou vibes are insane!?"
うるさい！！！！ていうか！！いるのいらないの！？どっち！
"Shut up!!!! I mean!! Do you want it or not!? Which is it!"
…うん、ありがとう。ありがたく受け取らせていただきます
"...Yeah, thank you. I will gladly accept it."
よろしい。メルとおそろいだよ！
"Very good. Now you match with Mel!"
これからもこんな私だけどよろしくね。大好きだよ
"Please keep taking care of me from now on too. I love you so much."
メルは少し照れながらかしこまった口調で微笑んだ。
Mel smiled in a formal tone, looking slightly bashful.
誰と会ってたの？って
"Asking 'Who were you meeting?'"
浮気してたの？って
"Asking 'Were you cheating on me?'"
子供じゃないんだし
I'm not a child anymore,
秘密くらいあるよ
so I have a secret or two.
全部なんて見せてちゃ続かない
If I show you everything, it won't last.
ケンカしてても
Even if we fight,
隣で寝ること
we sleep side by side.
これからの約束ね
That's our promise from now on.
返事！
Answer me!
いくつになっても恋させてよ あなたに
No matter how old we get, let me stay in love with you.
カッコ悪いとこは見ないようにしてあげるね
I'll pretend not to notice your uncool side.
愛もいいけど 恋していたい 私に
Love is good, but stay in love with me.
『綺麗だね』と言われるように 頑張るからね
I'll do my best so you'll tell me "You're beautiful".
嫌な事があった日
On days when bad things happen,
下手な料理で笑顔をありがとう
thank you for making me smile with your clumsy cooking.
合わない趣味ばかり
We barely share any hobbies,
もっと教えて これからの続き
so tell me more about what comes next.
家族増えても
Even as our family grows,
恋人がいいの
I still want us to be lovers.
お揃いも増やしてよ
Let's have more matching things too.
返事！
Answer me!
いくつになってもデートしてよ 記念日
No matter how old we get, go on dates with me on our anniversaries.
プレゼントはいらないくらい おしゃれしてね
Dress up so nicely that I won't even need a present.
晴れもいいけど 雨の日には くっついて
Sunny days are fine, but on rainy days, snuggle close.
ひとつの傘 揺らしながら 虹を待つの
Shaking a single umbrella as we wait for the rainbow.
いびきかいてた 寝てる隙に ほっぺにそっと キスしてること
While you were snoring asleep, I gently kissed your cheek,
気づかなかった？ 寝てる隙に 続けてくれてた
Didn't you notice? While I was asleep, you kept doing the same for me.
ダーリン ダーリン
Darling, Darling...
しわが増えても
Even when the wrinkles come,
甘えたいんだよ
I still want you to spoil me.
もちろん手も繋ぐこと
Of course, holding hands too.
返事！(ハイ！)
Reply! (Yes!)
いくつになっても 飽きないでね お願い
However old we get, don't get tired of me, please.
嫉妬しちゃうけど 頭撫でて 慰めてね
I'll get jealous, but pat my head and comfort me.
いつまでもずっと 恋していたい わたしに
I want to stay in love forever, so with me...
「綺麗だね」言われるように 頑張るから
I'll do my best so you tell me, "You're pretty,"
ね
Okay?
みんなのおかげで5周年を迎えられたよ！これからもたくさんの楽しい思い出つくっていこうね♪ Big LOVE♡だいすき！！
Thanks to everyone, I reached my 5th anniversary! Let's keep making lots of fun memories together. Big LOVE♡ I love you all!!
みんなのおかげで5周年を迎えられたよ！
Thanks to everyone, I was able to celebrate my 5th anniversary!
これからもたくさんの楽しい思い出つくっていこうね☺
Let's keep making lots of fun memories together from now on!
Big LOVE ♡ だいすき！！
Big LOVE ♡ I love you all!!